Register of the Bertram David Wolfe papers
Hoover Institution Archives
Bertram David Wolfe papers
1903-2000
77029
Hoover Institution Archives
183 manuscript boxes, 2 card file boxes, 2 oversize boxes, 35 envelopes, 6 microfilm reels, 5 videocassettes, 13 sound tape reels, 8 sound cassettes (85.2 linear feet)
Writings, correspondence, notes, memoranda, clippings, other printed matter, and audiovisual material relating to Marxism; the international communist movement; communism in the Soviet Union, the United States, and elsewhere; literature and art in the Soviet Union and in Mexico; and the Mexican artist Diego Rivera. Includes some papers of Rivera and papers of Ella Wolfe, wife of Bertram D. Wolfe. Digital copies of select records also available at https://digitalcollections.hoover.org.
Wolfe, Bertram David, 1896-1977.
Access
Box 183 closed; use copies available in box 12. Digital copies of select records also available at https://digitalcollections.hoover.org.
Use copies of some sound recordings, video recordings, or motion picture material in this collection are available for immediate access.
The Hoover Institution Archives only allows access to copies of audiovisual items. To listen to other sound recordings or to view other videos or films during your visit, please contact the Archives at least two working days before your arrival. We will then advise you of the accessibility of the material you wish to see or hear. Please note that not all audiovisual material is immediately accessible.
Acquisition Information
Acquired by the Hoover Institution Archives between 1977, with increments received from 1982 to 2015.
Accruals
Materials may have been added to the collection since this finding aid was prepared. To determine if this has occurred, find the collection in Stanford University's online catalog at http://searchworks.stanford.edu/. Materials have been added to the collection if the number of boxes listed in the online catalog is larger than the number of boxes listed in this finding aid.
Biographical Note
1896 January 19 Born, Brooklyn, New York
1916 B.A., College of the City of New York
1917 Married Ella Goldberg
1917-1919 Member, Socialist Party
1919-1929 Member, Communist Party, U.S.A.
1925-1928 Agitation and Propaganda Director, Communist Party
1928-1929 U.S. Representative, Executive Committee, Communist International
1929-1940 Affiliated with Lovestoneite opposition party
1931 M.A., Columbia University
1939 Author, Diego Rivera: His Life and Times
1948 Author, Three Who Made a Revolution
1950-1954 Chief Ideological Adviser, International Broadcasting Division, U.S. Department of State
1956 Author, Six Keys to the Soviet System
1957 Author, Khrushchev and Stalin's Ghost
1961-1962 Distinguished Visiting Professor, University of California, Davis
1963 Author, The Fabulous Life of Diego Rivera
1965 Author, Marxism: 100 Years in the Life of a Doctrine, and Strange Communists I Have Known
1966-1977 Senior Research Fellow, Hoover Institution on War, Revolution and Peace
1967 Author, The Bridge and the Abyss: The Troubled Friendship of Maxim Gorky and V. I. Lenin
1969 Author, An Ideology in Power: Reflections on the Russian Revolution
1977 February 21 Died, Palo Alto, California
Scope and Content of Collection
Writings, correspondence, notes, memoranda, clippings, other printed matter, and audiovisual material relating to Marxism; the international communist movement; communism in the Soviet Union, the United States, and elsewhere; literature and art in the Soviet Union and in Mexico; and the Mexican artist Diego Rivera. Includes some papers of Rivera and papers of Ella Wolfe, wife of Bertram D. Wolfe.
Scope and Content of the Incremental Materials
The materials in the increment consist largely of correspondence, writings, and printed matter added to the collection by Bertram D. Wolfe's widow, Ella Wolfe, in the years following his death in 1977. Additional items became part of the papers after Ella Wolfe's death in 2000. Much of the incremental materials pertain to Bertram Wolfe's career as a critic and historian of Marxism and Soviet communism, as well as his work as a biographer of Diego Rivera. They also document Ella Wolfe's role as her husband's collaborator and caretaker of his legacy, while showing her as a personality in her own right with a wide network of friends and correspondents.
The Speeches and Writings series of the papers contains an unpublished, book length manuscript by Bertram Wolfe, "The Corrido in Mexico." A work of cultural anthropology, this study explores how the corrido, a folk ballad form, has served as a vehicle for the expression of popular sentiment in Mexico, including as a means of commentary on various topical issues. In this series there is also a rare pamphlet in Spanish containing a text written by Wolfe during his visit to Spain in 1937, at the height of the Civil War. The series additionally includes the typescript draft of Bertram Wolfe's autobiography, A Life in Two Centuries, and the proofs of another posthumously published work, Revolution and Reality.
The Correspondence series records Bertram Wolfe's dealings with his publishers, as well as his exchanges with a number of colleagues in the fields of Soviet history and Marxist studies. A substantial amount of the correspondence relates to Ella Wolfe and her many friends and acquaintances. Included in this are many letters written to Ella Wolfe by Svetlana Allilueva, the daughter of Joseph Stalin. The Writings by Others series includes a number of unpublished papers, mainly relating to Soviet history, Marxism, and the Spanish Civil War.
The Photographs series includes many pictures of Bertram and Ella Wolfe. There are also several hundred photographs that depict paintings, sketches, and murals by Diego Rivera. These were used by Bertram Wolfe in the preparation of his book, The Fabulous Life of Diego Rivera. There are copies of a number of books by Bertram Wolfe, including Italian, Spanish, and German translations of some of them, in the Printed Matter series of the increment.
The Biographical File contains materials such as college yearbooks and membership cards, as a well as number of tributes to Bertram Wolfe written after his death. It also includes the transcript of an oral history interview with Ella Wolfe.
Scope and Content of the 2015 Incremental Materials
The 2015 increment consists of biographical materials, correspondence, writings, photographs, printed matter, and a subject file largely related to Bertram Wolfe. Received from a family member, this increment includes letters, writings, and other materials sent by Wolfe to members of his family, including his brothers Paul and Henry and his niece Evelyn (Rinna), as well as Wolfe's subject file on communist/USSR apologists.
Alternate Forms Available
Digital copies of select records also available at https://digitalcollections.hoover.org.
Communist International.; Communist Party of the United States of America.; Lenin, Vladimir Il'ich, 1870-1924.; Marx, Karl, 1818-1883.; Rivera, Diego, 1886-1957.; Wolfe, Ella.; Art--Mexico.; Audiotapes.; Communism and culture.; Communism--United States.; Communism.; Mexico; Russian literature.; Soviet Union--Politics and government.; Spain--History--Civil War, 1936-1939.; Video tapes.
- Biographical File, 1919-1977 (Box 1)
  Scope and Contents note
  Biographical data and writings, memorabilia, correspondence, clippings, and notices of speeches relating to the life of Bertram D. Wolfe, arranged by subject.
  - General
    - Autobiographical statements, 1939-1972; Holographs and typescripts. (Folder 1: 1)
    - Bibliographies, undated; Typescripts. (Folder 1: 2)
    - Biographical sketches, 1946-1976 (Folder 1: 3)
      Typescript, printed copies, and correspondence.
    - Biography, 1975 (Folder 1: 4)
      Butler, Joel P., "Bertram D. Wolfe: Radical Visions, but Few Illusions," typescript.
    - Clippings, 1943-1977; Printed copies. (Folder 1: 5-6)
    - Correspondence, 1946-1976 (Folder 1: 7)
    - Eulogy, 1977 (Folder 1: 8)
      Hook, Sidney, "A Farewell to Bertram D. Wolfe," typescript.
    - Miscellany, 1919-1975 (Folder 1: 9)
      Notes, notices of awards, certificates, etc.
    - Notices of lectures, 1927-1976; Typescript, mimeograph, and printed copies. (Folder 1: 10-11)
  - Communist parties, 1922-1936 (Folder 1: 12-13)
    Correspondence, minute questionnaire response, memorabilia, membership cards, and dues cards (typescript and printed) relating to the membership of Bertram D. Wolfe in the Communist Party and Communist Party (Opposition) and to his expulsion from the Communist Party.
  - Russian opinion, 1967-1972 (Folder 1: 14)
    Newspaper and periodical articles (printed in Russian), with translations (typescript), relating to the assessment of the scholarly work of Bertram D. Wolfe by Russian writers.
  - Spain, visit to, 1937 (Folder 1: 15)
    Passes, safe-conducts, and letters of introduction (holograph and typescript in Spanish, Catalan and English), relating to the visit of Bertram D. Wolfe to Spain during the Spanish Civil War.
  - Voice of America, 1949-1954 (Folder 1: 16-17)
    Correspondence, memoranda, clippings, applications, performance ratings, interrogatory testimony, and loyalty statement (typescript, mimeograph and print) relating to the work of Bertram D. Wolfe for the Voice of America, to allegations regarding his loyalty to the government, and to governmental investigations of his loyalty.
- Correspondence, 1913-1977 (Boxes 2-16)
  Correspondence of Bertram and Ella Wolfe, arranged alphabetically by correspondent.
  - Unidentified (10), 1937-1974 (Folder 2: 1)
  - Abramovitch, Raphael (1), 1947 (Folder 2: 2)
  - Abreu Gomez, Emilio (1), undated (Folder 2: 3)
  - Accuracy in Media (2), 1973 (Folder 2: 4)
  - Acheson, Dean (1), 1950 (Folder 2: 5)
  - Ad Hoc Committee for Intellectual Freedom (3), 1973 (Folder 2: 6)
  - Ad Hoc Protest Committee (2), 1975 (Folder 2: 7)
  - Adamiak, Richard (1), 1970 (Folder 2: 8)
  - Aguirre, Jose Antonio de (2), 1944 (Folder 2: 9)
  - Akron, Ohio, University of (1), 1969 (Folder 2: 10)
  - Alba, Victor (3), 1964-1970 (Folder 2: 11)
  - Albertini, G. (4), 1966-1974 (Folder 2: 12)
  - Alexander, Robert J. (11), 1948-1971 (Folder 2: 13)
  - Alfred A. Knopf Company (10), 1944-1967 (Folder 2: 14)
  - Allen, Martha Rutledge (1), 1956 (Folder 2: 15)
  - Allen, Richard V. (3), 1966-1969 (Folder 2: 16)
  - Allen, Mrs. William Dangaix (1), 1946 (Folder 2: 17)
  - Almond, Gabriel A. (1), 1971 (Folder 2: 18)
  - Ambrose, Paul B. (2), 1971-1972 (Folder 2: 19)
  - America First Committee (2), 1941 (Folder 2: 20)
  - American Academy of Arts and Sciences (3), 1975 (Folder 2: 21)
  - American Academy of Political and Social Science. Annals (2), 1969 (Folder 2: 22)
  - American Association for the Advancement of Slavic Studies (13), 1967-1974 (Folder 2: 23)
  - American Association of University Women (2), 1944 (Folder 2: 24)
  - American Bar Association (3), 1964-1966 (Folder 2: 25)
  - American Book Company (1), 1963 (Folder 2: 26)
  - American Council for World Freedom (1), 1976 (Folder 2: 27)
  - American Foundation for Continuing Education (2), 1959 (Folder 2: 28)
  - American Heritage Publishing Company (3), 1959-1968 (Folder 2: 29)
  - American Jewish Committee (1), 1951 (Folder 2: 30)
  - American Jewish Year Book (1), 1952 (Folder 2: 31)
  - American Mercury (21), 1944-1950 (Folder 2: 32)
  - American Political Science Review (7), 1967-1975 (Folder 2: 33)
  - American Slavic and East European Review (4), 1957-1958 (Folder 2: 34)
  - American University, Washington, D.C., Special Operations Research Office (2), 1959 (Folder 2: 35)
  - American Writers Association (2), 1947-1949 (Folder 2: 36)
  - Andrade, Juan (3), 1940 (Folder 2: 37)
  - Andreski, Stanislav (2), 1973 (Folder 2: 38)
  - Antioch Review (14), 1961-1971 (Folder 2: 39)
  - Arab World (3), 1945 (Folder 2: 40)
  - Arahata, Kanson (3), 1956-1960 (Folder 2: 41)
  - Armstrong, David (2), undated (Folder 2: 42)
  - Aron, Raymond (2), 1965-1972 (Folder 2: 43)
  - Aronson, Gregor (4), 1959 (Folder 2: 44)
  - Arquer, Jordi (1), 1940 (Folder 2: 45)
  - Arrow, Kenneth J. (2), 1975 (Folder 2: 46)
  - Ascher, Abraham (9), 1967-1975 (Folder 2: 47)
  - Atlantic Monthly (2), 1959 (Folder 2: 48)
  - Australian Association for Cultural Freedom (1), 1958 (Folder 2: 49)
  - Authors Guild (2), 1947-1969 (Folder 2: 50)
  - Avakumovic, Ivan (1), 1957 (Folder 2: 51)
  - Avineri, Shlomo (1), 1967 (Folder 2: 52)
  - Avrich, Paul (3), 1974 (Folder 2: 53)
  - Azrael, Jeremy R. (1), 1971 (Folder 2: 54)
  - Baarslag, Karl (7), 1966-1970 (Folder 2: 55)
  - Baer, Louis Shattuck (1), 1971 (Folder 2: 56)
  - Baevsky, Sonya (2), 1976 (Folder 2: 57)
  - Bailes, Kendall E. (1), 1974 (Folder 2: 58)
  - Bailey, Helga L. (2), 1972 (Folder 2: 59)
  - Balabanoff, Angelica (190), 1941-1965 (Folder 2: 60-62)
  - Baldwin, Hanson W. (3), 1975 (Folder 3: 1)
  - Baldwin, Roger N. (4), 1941-1974 (Folder 3: 2)
  - Bales, Frank N. (3), 1972 (Folder 3: 3)
  - Bales, James D. (3), 1959-1963 (Folder 3: 4)
  - Ballestrem, Karl G. (3), 1971 (Folder 3: 5)
  - Baltimore Open Forum (2), 1941 (Folder 3: 6)
  - Bank of America (4), 1966-1969 (Folder 3: 7)
  - Barghoorn, Frederick C. (4), 1958-1972 (Folder 3: 8)
  - Bark, William C. (4), 1971-1973 (Folder 3: 9)
  - Barker, Nancy N. (3), 1970 (Folder 3: 10)
  - Barnett, Arthur G. (3), 1948 (Folder 3: 11)
  - Baron, Sam (2), 1956-1963 (Folder 3: 12)
  - Basen, Neil K. (5), 1975 (Folder 3: 13)
  - Bassett, T. D. Seymour (2), 1947 (Folder 3: 14)
  - Bauer, Peter T. (5), 1972 (Folder 3: 15)
  - Baylen, Joseph O. (2), 1971 (Folder 3: 16)
  - Beacon Press (7), 1955-1967 (Folder 3: 17)
  - Beagle, Peter S. (3), 1972-1976 (Folder 3: 18)
  - Beals, Carleton (3), 1956-1958 (Folder 3: 19)
  - Becker, Abram G. (1), 1951 (Folder 3: 20)
  - Behrendt, Richard F. (3), 1944-1947 (Folder 3: 21)
  - Beichman, Arnold (1), undated (Folder 3: 22)
  - Belding, Don (2), 1967 (Folder 3: 23)
  - Bell, Daniel (4), 1956-1971 (Folder 3: 24)
  - Berberova, Nina (2), 1973 (Folder 3: 25)
  - Berch, Victor A. (2), 1970 (Folder 3: 26)
  - Bergman, Jay (2), 1973-1974 (Folder 3: 27)
  - Bergson, Abram (2), 1975 (Folder 3: 28)
  - Bernal, Ignacio (1), 1974 (Folder 3: 29)
  - Bernard, David E. (1), 1949 (Folder 3: 30)
  - Billikopf, Jacob (1), 1947 (Folder 3: 31)
  - Billington, James H. (1), 1970 (Folder 3: 32)
  - Bittson, Anthony John (8), 1972-1974 (Folder 3: 33)
  - Black, Cyril E. (1), 1967 (Folder 3: 34)
  - Black, Virginia (2), 1974 (Folder 3: 35)
  - Blackstock, Paul W. (1), 1968 (Folder 3: 36)
  - Blake, Patricia (18), 1968-1973 (Folder 3: 37)
  - Bliven, Bruce (4), 1969-1970 (Folder 3: 38)
  - Block, Herbert (1), 1969 (Folder 3: 39)
  - Bloom, Solomon F. (2), 1949 (Folder 3: 40)
  - Bloque Obrero Marxista de Mexico (3), 1937 (Folder 3: 41)
  - Bobbs-Merrill Company (1), 1946 (Folder 3: 42)
  - Boiter, Albert (7), 1961-1973 (Folder 3: 43)
  - Bolloten, Burnett (4), 1973-1976 (Folder 3: 44)
  - Book Find Club (2), 1950 (Folder 3: 45)
  - Books Abroad (3), 1943 (Folder 3: 46)
  - Books for the Blind of Arizona (2), 1971 (Folder 3: 47)
  - Borkenau, Franz (1), 1971 (Folder 3: 48)
  - Borochowicz, Leo and Elly (6), 1937-1976 (Folder 3: 49)
  - Boston Globe (2), 1967 (Folder 3: 50)
  - Boston University (4), 1965-1972 (Folder 3: 51)
  - Bourguina, Anna (2), 1969 (Folder 3: 52)
  - Boyden, Polly (1), unfsyrf (Folder 3: 53)
  - Brandeis University (2), 1949 (Folder 3: 54)
  - Brandin, Alf E. (3), 1972 (Folder 3: 55)
  - Brandler, Heinrich (1), 1937 (Folder 3: 56)
  - Brangwyn, Rodney (1), 1969 (Folder 3: 57)
  - Brett, James Q. (1), 1974 (Folder 3: 58)
  - Brewer, Renee Hirt (4), 1972 (Folder 3: 59)
  - Brigham Young University (5), 1971-1972 (Folder 3: 60)
  - Brock, Michael G. (2), 1959-1960 (Folder 3: 61)
  - Brockway, Fenner (2), 1937-1956 (Folder 3: 62)
  - Brooklyn College (1), undated (Folder 3: 63)
  - Brooklyn Museum (4), 1971 (Folder 3: 64)
  - Brooklyn Women's Club (1), undated (Folder 3: 65)
  - Browder, Robert Paul (3), 1960-1972 (Folder 3: 66)
  - Brown, Edward J. (2), 1968-1971 (Folder 3: 67)
  - Brown, Irving (5), 1947-1976 (Folder 3: 68)
  - Brown University (3), 1956 (Folder 3: 69)
  - Brownell, William (2), 1976 (Folder 3: 70)
  - Brumberg, Abraham (30), 1954-1970 (Folder 3: 71)
  - Bryn Mawr College (1), 1949 (Folder 3: 72)
  - Buckley, William F., Jr. (8), 1970-1975 (Folder 3: 73)
  - Buhle, Paul (1), 1968 (Folder 3: 74)
  - Bunzel, John H. (2), 1973 (Folder 3: 75)
  - Burke, Donald L. (2), 1972 (Folder 3: 76)
  - Burks, David D. (1), 1956 (Folder 3: 77)
  - Burnham, James (4), 1969-1970 (Folder 3: 78)
  - Busbey, Representative Fred E. (1), 1953 (Folder 3: 79)
  - Calder, Alexander, III (10), 1971-1973 (Folder 3: 80)
  - California State College, Hayward (3), 1968 (Folder 3: 81)
  - California State University, Fresno (2), 1973 (Folder 3: 82)
  - California, University of (1), 1962 (Folder 3: 83)
  - California, University of, Extension Center (2), 1970 (Folder 3: 84)
  - California, University of, Riverside (2), 1971 (Folder 3: 85)
  - California, University of, Los Angeles (5), 1966-1971 (Folder 3: 86)
  - Call (New York) (1), undated (Folder 4: 1)
  - Calleo, David P. (1), 1971 (Folder 4: 2)
  - Canaday, John (3), 1969 (Folder 4: 3)
  - Canadian Institute of International Affairs (1), 1956 (Folder 4: 4)
  - Carey, George W. (3), 1973 (Folder 4: 5)
  - Carlson, Oliver (5), 1974-1976 (Folder 4: 6)
  - Carmichael, Joel (4), 1969-1973 (Folder 4: 7)
  - Carney, Jack (1), 1940 (Folder 4: 8)
  - Carr, E. H. (3), 1960 (Folder 4: 9)
  - Carre de Vivanco, Ines (2), 1948 (Folder 4: 10)
  - Carrillo, Rafael (22), 1924-1929 (Folder 4: 11)
  - Carter, President James E. (2), 1977 (Folder 4: 12)
  - Catholic Digest (1), 1945 (Folder 4: 13)
  - Caylor, George N. (3), 1966-1967 (Folder 4: 14)
  - Cerf, Bennett A. (1), undated (Folder 4: 15)
  - Chamberlin, William Henry (3), 1943-1951 (Folder 4: 16)
  - Chambers, Whittaker (1), 1957 (Folder 4: 17)
  - Chang, Carsun (2), 1968 (Folder 4: 18)
  - Charlot, Jean (2), 1963 (Folder 4: 19)
  - Chavchavadze, Paul (1), 1969 (Folder 4: 20)
  - Cheek, James E. (2), 1969-1970 (Folder 4: 21)
  - Chen, Chih-mai (3), 1945-1946 (Folder 4: 22)
  - Chertok, Benson T. (29), 1970-1975 (Folder 4: 23)
  - Chicago Daily News (5), 1967-1968 (Folder 4: 24)
  - Chicago Sun (4), 1942-1943 (Folder 4: 25)
  - Chicago, University of, Press (2), 1965 (Folder 4: 26)
  - Childs, Marquis W. (2), 1970 (Folder 4: 27)
  - China, News Service (1), 1946 (Folder 4: 28)
  - Christenson, Reo M. (2), 1972 (Folder 4: 29)
  - Church, Peggy (1), 1949 (Folder 4: 30)
  - Cincinnati Times-Star (1), 1949 (Folder 4: 31)
  - Cisney, Jack E. (1), 1973 (Folder 4: 32)
  - City Club of New York (1), 1942 (Folder 4: 33)
  - Clague, Ewan (2), 1970 (Folder 4: 34)
  - Claremont Men's College (2), 1966 (Folder 4: 35)
  - Clariana, Bernardo (1), 1943 (Folder 4: 36)
  - Clark, Charles Upson (18), 1946-1960 (Folder 4: 37)
  - Clement, Travers (7), 1940-1948 (Folder 4: 38)
  - Clements, Barbara E. (2), 1973 (Folder 4: 39)
  - Clim, A. (1), 1927 (Folder 4: 40)
  - Closa, Antonio (1), 1941 (Folder 4: 41)
  - Coalition for an Academic Community (1), 1969 (Folder 4: 42)
  - Cohen, Stephen F. (30), 1971-1973 (Folder 4: 43)
  - Cohen, Wilbur (3), 1968 (Folder 4: 44)
  - Colebrook, Joan, (11), 1972 (Folder 4: 45)
  - Colegrove, Kenneth (1), 1960 (Folder 4: 46)
  - Collart, Yves (2), 1970 (Folder 4: 47)
  - Collier Books (1), 1962 (Folder 4: 48)
  - Collinet, Michel (2), 1967 (Folder 4: 49)
  - Columbia Broadcasting System (8), 1964-1968 (Folder 4: 50)
  - Columbia University (3), 1950-1971 (Folder 4: 51)
  - Columbia University, Russian Institute (18), 1949-1960 (Folder 4: 52)
  - Commentary (7), 1955-1958 (Folder 4: 53)
  - Committee for the Aid of Refugee Ukrainian Scholars (2), 1946 (Folder 4: 54)
  - Committee on Academic Nondiscrimination and Integrity (2), 1974-1975 (Folder 4: 55)
  - Committee on Cooperation in Latin America (1), 1947 (Folder 4: 56)
  - Committee on the Present Danger (2), 1977 (Folder 4: 57)
  - Committee to Re-Elect the President (1), 1972 (Folder 4: 58)
  - Common Sense (2), 1945-1946 (Folder 4: 59)
  - Conference of American Small Business Organizations (1), 1961 (Folder 4: 60)
  - Confino, Michael (2), 1976 (Folder 4: 61)
  - Conolly, Violet (1), 1970 (Folder 4: 62)
  - Conquest, Robert (7), 1966-1971 (Folder 4: 63)
  - Constas, Helen (2), 1968 (Folder 4: 64)
  - Contemporary Jewish Record (1), 1945 (Folder 4: 65)
  - Controversy (1), 1937 (Folder 4: 66)
  - Conyngham, William (7), 1971-1973 (Folder 4: 67)
  - Cook, Chet (2), 1939-1943 (Folder 4: 68)
  - Coordinating Committee of American-Polish Association in the East (3), 1945 (Folder 4: 69)
  - Coors, Joseph (5), 1972-1975 (Folder 4: 70)
  - Corey, Lewis (15), 1936-1952 (Folder 4: 71)
  - Council against Communist Aggression (8), 1967-1973 (Folder 4: 72)
  - Council on African Affairs (1), 1948 (Folder 4: 73)
  - Council on Foreign Relations (5), 1946-1975 (Folder 4: 74)
  - Counts, George S. (3), 1971-1972 (Folder 4: 75)
  - Covici-Friede Publishers (13), 1935-1948 (Folder 4: 76)
  - Cox, Richard H. (1), 1965 (Folder 4: 77)
  - Cranston, Maurice (3), 1973-1976 (Folder 4: 78)
  - Crocker, George N. (6), 1968-1969 (Folder 4: 79)
  - Crow, John A. (1), undated (Folder 4: 80)
  - Current Digest of the Soviet Press (2), 1968-1969 (Folder 4: 81)
  - Current History (1), 1956 (Folder 4: 82)
  - Curtiss, John S. (3), 1958 (Folder 4: 83)
  - Dailey, Kenneth I. (2), 1970 (Folder 5: 1)
  - Daily Oklahoman (1), 1973 (Folder 5: 2)
  - Dallin, Alexander (7), 1949-1971 (Folder 5: 3)
  - Dallin, David J. (1), 1950 (Folder 5: 4)
  - Daniels, Robert V. (1), 1960 (Folder 5: 5)
  - Dartmouth College (3), 1969-1970 (Folder 5: 6)
  - Davis, Harry R. (1), 1968 (Folder 5: 7)
  - Davis, Dr. Joseph (6), 1971-1975 (Folder 5: 8)
  - Davis, Robert (2), 1944-1958 (Folder 5: 9)
  - Debo, Richard K. (9), 1972-1973 (Folder 5: 10)
  - Decter, Midge (2), 1975 (Folder 5: 11)
  - Decter, Moshe (5), 1957-1965 (Folder 5: 12)
  - De George, Richard T. (1), 1970 (Folder 5: 13)
  - Degras, Jane (1), 1971 (Folder 5: 14)
  - Dejevsky, Mary (2), 1976 (Folder 5: 15)
  - De Leon, Margaret (1), 1949 (Folder 5: 16)
  - Dell Publishing Company (1), 1962 (Folder 5: 17)
  - Dellin, L. A. D. (1), 1963 (Folder 5: 18)
  - Delson, Robert (1), 1959 (Folder 5: 19)
  - Depuy, Catherine (1), 1972 (Folder 5: 20)
  - Deutsch, Babette (3), 1945-1965 (Folder 5: 21)
  - Dial Press (5), 1965-1972 (Folder 5: 22)
  - Didier Publishers (1), 1946 (Folder 5: 23)
  - Diggins, John P. (5), 1971-1974 (Folder 5: 24)
  - Djilas, Milovan (1), 1972 (Folder 5: 25)
  - Doenecke, Justus D. (3), 1970 (Folder 5: 26)
  - Doubleday and Company (3), 1960-1968 (Folder 5: 27)
  - Douglas, Senator Paul H. (4), 1966-1972 (Folder 5: 28)
  - Douglass, Elaine (2), 1972 (Folder 5: 29)
  - Douse, Major George H. (1), 1973 (Folder 5: 30)
  - Doyle, Lieutenant Colonel William L., Jr. (2), 1974 (Folder 5: 31)
  - Draper, Hal (1), 1962 (Folder 5: 32)
  - Draper, Theodore (17), 1956-1975 (Folder 5: 33)
  - Drucker, Erich (8), 1968 (Folder 5: 34)
  - Duckles, Edwin L. (8), 1943-1953 (Folder 5: 35)
  - Dulles, Eleanor Lansing (6), 1970-1976 (Folder 5: 36)
  - Dunne, William F. (1), 1926 (Folder 5: 37)
  - Duval, Charles (3), 1974 (Folder 5: 38)
  - Ealum, Maurice (1), 1956 (Folder 5: 39)
  - Earhart Foundation (47), 1970-1976 (Folder 5: 40)
  - Eastman, Max (12), 1944-1959 (Folder 5: 41)
  - Ebon, Martin (2), 1967 (Folder 5: 42)
  - Echeverria, President Luis (5), 1974-1976 (Folder 5: 43)
  - Edgerton, William B. (10), 1943-1971 (Folder 5: 44)
  - Editorial Ercilla (35), 1940-1943 (Folder 5: 45)
  - Edwards, Owen Dudley (1), 1973 (Folder 5: 46)
  - Ehrenreich, Joan (1), 1973 (Folder 5: 47)
  - Einstein, Albert (2), 1934-1947 (Folder 5: 48)
  - Eissenstat, Bernard W. (32), 1965-1976 (Folder 5: 49)